Mariia Paraketsova







Phone: 0722 00 00 41

Email: paraketsova@gmail.com

Adress: Virebergsvägen 16, Solna

paraketsova.com, paraketsova.github.io github.com/paraketsova

linkedin.com/in/mariia-paraketsova-2a3513154/

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Fullstack Web Developer, ServiceNow administrator/Developer with experience in both development and project management. I also have an Engineer's Degree in Chemical Technology. Skilled in both frontend and backend development and has worked with various technologies and frameworks, including JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Angular, MySQL, MariaDB, MongoDB,

Git, Node.js etc.

IT SKILS

JavaScript, TypeScript React, Next.js

ServiceNow

Angular, Node.js **REST APIs** C#, PHP

MySQL, MongoDB, MariaDB

Webflow

Git, Agile, Scrum

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

www.midlibrary.io 2023 - nuvarande **Fullstack Developer**

- Developing most advanced library of genres, artistic movements, techniques, titles, and artists' styles for Midjourney Al
- JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, WebFlow, Airtable, n8n

Scania Group 2021 - 2022 Software engineer Intern

- Developing UI and implementing frontend and backend parts of new Scania Booking System
- Frontend: Angular, Angular Material, Scania Digital Design System Backend: C# backend API, Entity Framework, MySQL, AWS Lambda

GitLab CI/CD

SST Group | BARTEC GMBH 1999 - 2014 **Project Manager**

· Led Industrial Heating Cable Systems Projects

EDUCATION

2020 - 2022

2023 - nuvarande ServiceNow-Administrator && Developer

Lexicon Stockholm / Hibdigital London

Web Developer Fullstack open source

Nackademin YH, Solna

· JavaScript, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, React, MySQL, MongoDB, PHP, CMS, Git, Agile

1992 - 1998 **Engineer of chemical technology**

Moscow State University of Fine Chemical Technologies

VOLUNTEERING

2020 - current **Frontend Developer** FreeFeed

JavaScript, Next.js

2023 ADHD-center, Stockholm Interpreter

English, Swedish, Russian **LANGUAGES**

CITIZENSHIP Sweden